Samarpan Rai

Data Scientist

Nijmegen, Netherlands

0625297625 samarpan-rai@live.com

Personal Statement

Studying bachelors of Artificial Intelligence (BsC) at Radboud university in the Netherlands. Past life, engineer with experience in electronics/electrical and Web development.

Worked in projects ranging from embedded circuit development for a creative agency in Kathmandu(Nepal), API Developer for a startup company in Paris (France), Social Media Manager for Radboud University (Netherlands) to Product Manager for startup company in Nijmegen (Netherlands).

Experience

GooHoo / Data Scientist

Nov 2018 - PRESENT, Nijmegen, Netherlands

My job as Data Scientist at GooHoo is quite open-ended. Being a fairly new young company from the perspective of Data Science, I am responsible for laying out the architecture needed for all processes. However, I am still a student so by researching the best-practices around Data Science, my task now revolves around the following points:

- ◆ Researching latest papers about Retail and Operations management focusing on Demand forecasting. Furthermore, translating abstract business problems to concrete data science problems.
- ◆ Create data pipelines to process and transform data from diverse sources and prototype dashboards in Shiny to provide actionable business insights.
- ♦ On top, build algorithm for dynamically pricing multiple products to maximize revenue

Eye Sense / Product Manager

Feb 2018 - Aug 2018, Nijmegen

This internship was a unique experience for me because my target clients were blind or visually impaired. This demanded me to think about solutions in creative manner. For example a simple sidebar menu is not a sidebar at all. My day to day task at EyeSense revolved around the following points:

- ♦ Create proper data flow from customer to developers by understanding to user's need and translating them to developers.
- ◆ Monitor user's interaction with the app to gain knowledge about how HCI (Human-computer-Interaction) elements can be improved.
- ◆ Report weekly data analysis (using Sci-kit, numpy, pandas etc) about the user experience

WYND / Web Integration Developer

Nov 2015 - May 2016, Paris, France

My role at WYND was to create a new API framework to communicate with mobile devices. My day to day revolved around the following tasks:

- ullet Investigating, proposing and providing solutions for cheaper communication between remote autonomous payment devices. With my provided solution we were able to save ~60% on mobile data usage.
- ♦ Extensive API development and Symfony2 integration along with SlimAPI platform and providing detail on usage of the API.
- ◆ Testing system architecture and server management and migration

Education

Radboud University / Bachelors of Science (Artificial Intelligence)

2016 - 2020, Netherlands

Intensive bachelors study that combines Psychology, Cognitive Science, Computer Science and Mathematics together to mold a holistic approach to Artificial Intelligence. Along with building Neural Networks, I was asked to question the ethical perspective of AI to our modern society.

Ullens School/IBDP

2012 - 2014, Nepal

Two years of rigorous Baccalaureate course that incorporates subjects like CAS and TOK. To be eligible for the diploma, I wrote a 4000 word research paper on the topic: Efficiency of operational amplifier

Volunteer Experience

Mentor / Coderdojo Nijmegen

2018 - Present. Netherlands

Every first Sunday of the month, I mentor teach kids between the ages of 7 and 16 during the coderdojo sessions.

Developer / Himalayan disaster

2014, Nepal

After the destructive 7.8M earthquake that hit Nepal on 12th May 2015, relief material being quickly being distributed to the affected villages of Nepal but there was not a system present to keep track of those relief work. These created a problem as there was no way to check the hotspot for relief.

We created a data collection and visualization platform to keep track of these relief measures. This helped the organizations and volunteering groups of people to take better decisions.

The system is is fully open source and can be found in github.